在上一集中
Previously on Transformers Prime...
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
Download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前 得到铁堡的遗物
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do
我们就必须分头行动
we must divide our resources.
派出多支小队 同时前往这四个地点
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
我将前往南极
I will embark for the Antarctica.
至于你 我的老朋友
As for you, old friend
我想让一个人陪同你执行任务
I would prefer that you have company on your mission.
你不是认真的吧！
You can't be serious.
千斤顶桀骜不驯 粗俗无礼！
Wheeljack is insubordinate, a ruffian!
千斤顶是个强大的战士
Wheeljack is a highly capable warrior.
由他暂时陪同对你有好处
You would be wise to welcome the temporary alliance.
头儿认为你需要支援 嗯？
The boss thought you needed backup, huh?
如果你一定要知道
If you must know
擎天柱强烈认为你需要监督！
Optimus feels strongly that you require supervision.
我会好好表现的 大夫
I'll be sure to be on my best behavior, Doc.
请不要叫我“大夫”！
Please, don't call me "Doc".
随便你怎么说 阳光老男孩
Whatever you say... sunshine.
呃…
En...
这么说 领袖卫队都去忙着寻找四个铁堡遗物了？
So, all of team Prime's busy chasing down these four Iacon relics?
这是目前所知的四个
The four which are currently in play.
还有更多？
There's more?
威震天拥有整个铁堡数据库
Megatron maintains possession of the entire Iacon database.
我们需要查出其中还包含多少遗物
We have yet to learn how many more relics
或是霸天虎的大规模杀伤性武器
or Decepticon weapons of mass destruction it contains.
别担心 大夫 我来罩着你！
No worries, Doc. I've got your back.
哦 我的名字不是“大夫”
My name is not "Doc"!
而且我也不需要任何人来帮忙！
And I do not require anyone watching my back!
在塞博特恩之战中我已经证实了自己的能力
I proved my metal during the war for Cybertron.
那我很荣幸能有你同行 战神
Then I'm lucky you're along for the ride, champ.
看来我们带了个尾巴
'Cause we got a bogie on our tail.
声波！
Soundwave!
威震天的通讯官？
Megatron's communications chief?
他一定也在追踪这个遗物
He must be tracking the same coordinates.
你最好抓紧扶手！
You might want to grab on to something.
你是想把咱们都送进废料场吗？
Are you trying to send us to the scrap yard?
那是什么？
What's that?
声波的放哨喽罗 激光鸟！
Soundwave's surveillance drone, Laserbeak.
千斤顶 继续追击！
Wheeljack, maintain pursuit!
声波只是用它来转移我们的注意力！
Soundwave is merely using the drone to distract us.
我喜欢这个干扰
I welcome a good distraction.
猎人变成猎物了
The hunter becomes the hunted.
没时间进行追捕游戏了！
This is no time to be hot-dogging.
他跑了 现在我们要去找到声波…哇噢！
He is gone. Now, we can go find Soundwave.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
千斤顶？千――斤――顶――！
Wheeljack? Wheeljaaack!
吃得消吗 虎子？
Took up that, Con!
你打中了！
You did it!
啊…右侧推进器烧毁了！
Right thruster's fried.
如果你听我的去追声波…
If you had pursuit Soundwave as I instructed...
他的小鸟还是会来啄我们的排气管！
His little birdie would still be pecking at our tailpipes.
好吧 我们需要立刻继续追踪遗物！
Well, we need to resume our search for the relic immediately.
声波没准儿已经找到它了！
Soundwave may already have reached it.
钻击号飞不了啦
The Jackhammer is not going anywhere.
要想追上那个虎子
If you wanna catch that Con
我们得靠轮子！
we need to roll.
那快决定啊！
Make up your mind.
是步行还是开过去？
Are we walking or are we driving?
千斤顶 注意保持距离！
Wheeljack, keep your distance.
激光鸟是声波的耳目！
Laserbeak is the eyes and ears of Soundwave.
它现在什么也不是了！
Not anymore, it isn't.
操作系统仍然完好 但停机了
Operating system appears functional but offline.
看来撞击损坏了它的光学和音频接收器
However the crash clearly damaged its optic and audio receptors.
看来有人得换侦察兵了！
Guess someone's gonna need a new snitch.
小胜一局 这不是我们此行的目的
A minor victory and not the one we're here to achieve.
在这等一会儿 大夫
Hang on there, Doc.
啊！
Oh!
这形势正适合玩一个老把戏
Situation's right for an old wrecker trick.
我…我不太明白
I am... not sure I follow.
声波早晚会寻回他的宠物
Sooner or later Soundwave's gonna come looking for his pet.
我们可以让他们重逢 回到基地
We let them reunite and return to base
同时带去一个手雷！
packing a light grenade.
等到声波去摸里面
The first time 'Wave reaches inside
他就会碰触到机关 然后 卡――砰！
it rips the bang and kaboom!
与其植入一个小小的燃烧弹
Why plant a mere insanitary device?
何不植入一个更具毁灭性的炸弹呢？
When we could plant a more devastating bomb.
一个病毒！
A virus.
通过激光鸟来感染声波
Engineered to pass from Laserbeak to Soundwave.
然后 直接侵入霸天虎战舰的主机
Then directly into the Decepticon warship's mainframe
通过它将整个铁堡数据库传送给我们
where it will transmit the content of the entire Iacon database to us.
听上去挺复杂 咱们不是在赶时间吗？
Sounds complicated. Thought we were in a hurry.
擎天柱会认同的
Optimus would agree.
赌上一个遗物 换取其余所有的遗物 值得一搏
Risking the loss of one relic to gain the rest is a worthwhile gamble.
你真的有能力编好这样的程序？
You really have a chance to pull off that kind of programming?
嗯…我一个人不行 还需要个帮手
Not alone. I will require backup.
拉斐尔 我们这里有情况
Raphael. We have a situation.
如果你能编写一段病毒源代码
If you could write a source code for the virus
我的扫描仪可以\N在上传过程中将它转译为塞博特恩代码
my scanner will translate it to Cybertronian script as it uploads.
我能行！
I can do it.
但如果我们想让病毒骗过虎子
but if you wanna keep the virus hidden from the 'Cons
我们需要一个诱饵 你知道的
we'll need a decoy, you know,
比如伪装病毒
like a second virus.
可以更简单一点
Or something less complicated.
诱饵的意思是 我们希望被他们发现
A decoy as in... we wanted them to find it
但又不会爆炸？
but it doesn't blow?
正确
Correct.
可惜了一颗上好的手雷
Seems like a waste of a perfectly good grenade.
等等 手雷在激光鸟体内 激光鸟又在声波体内？
Wait a minute, a grenade inside of Laserbeak inside of Soundwave.
真像火鸭鸡！
Like a "turducken".
什么？
I'm sorry?
一个火鸡里填上鸭子 鸭子里填上…
It's a turkey stuffed with a duck, stuffed with...
…啊 算了！
nevermind.
你要去哪儿？
And where are you off to?
为你争取些时间 然后 说不定
To buy you some time, and who knows
还能捡个遗物回来
maybe to pick up a relic.
你东西掉了
You dropped something.
要玩点刺激的了
This should be fun.
我的拿手戏 不让人如愿
Here I go again... shattering expectations.
拉斐尔 我接入了激光鸟的上行传输器
Rafael, I jacked in the Laserbeak's supplying transmitter.
你准备好后 我会启动它的操作系统以接收数据
When you're ready I will bring its operating system back online and order it to receive the transfer.
有什么遗言吗？
Any last words?
对哦 闷骚型的
Right, silent type.
救护车 病毒编写完成 开始上传
Ratchet, the virus is coded. Commencing upload.
拉斐尔 我们的进展如何？
Rafael, what is our progress?
50%
50 percent.
呃 大夫？
Doc.
千斤顶 我告诉过你别那样叫我！
Wheeljack, I told you not to call me that!
对不起
I'm sorry.
怎么了？你在哪儿？
What's wrong, where are you?
我估计你还有两分钟
Think you got maybe... two minutes.
也许更少
Or less.
千斤顶你的情况如何？千斤顶？
Wheeljack, what is your condition? Wheeljack!
拉斐尔？
Rafael?
马上就好！
We're almost there.
完成！
Done.
糟了！
Scrap!
声波上钩了 千斤顶？
Soundwave has taken the bait. Wheeljack?
见鬼！
Scrap.
啊 共振炮！
The resonance blaster!
霸天虎科学家设计的最为强大的音波毁灭武器
Crafted by Decepticon scientist for maximum sonic devastation.
声波 你表现得很好
Soundwave, you have performed admirably
不像骇翼
unlike Dreadwing here
竟然将精锐护甲送到了红蜘蛛手上！
who somehow managed to loose the APEX armor to Starscream.
不过还有两组坐标
However, two more decrypted coordinates remain in play.
我很信任击倒 并且我…
And I have every confidence that Knockout and I...
你们能想象到汽车人对我做了什么吗？！
Can you believe what the autobots did to me?!
你找回遗物了吗？！
Did you retrieve the relic?
没有 主人
No, master.
那么我建议你现在修好激光鸟
Then I suggest you convince me of your continuing usefulness
以向我证明你仍有利用价值 医生
by examining Laserbeak, Doctor.
千斤顶！
Wheeljack!
啊 我只是休息下光学镜
Just resting my optics.
唔 和音频接收器
And my audio receptors.
怎么了？
What is it?
有某种阻塞物
An obstruction of some sort.
手雷！
Grenade!
啊 真聪明 击倒
Ah, that is clever. Knockout,
准备好去处理下这个“阻塞物”
prepare to properly dispose of the obstruction.
声波 如果我们想保持对汽车人的优势…
Soundwave, if we're to maintain any advantage over the Autobots
…破译剩余的铁堡数据仍是你的首要任务！
decoding the remainder of the Iacon database must remain your top priority.
拉斐尔 打开环陆桥
Rafael, send the groundbridge.
我还是建议你回到基地
I still advice that you return to base.
你需要全面的检查
You require a thorough examination.
我现在需要的是船体密封剂
The only thing I require right now is some hole sealant.
相信我 钻击号比我更需要修理
Trust me, the Jackhammer here is in more need of repair than me.
听着 千斤顶 我只是想…
Listen, Wheeljack. I want to...
谢谢你的…支援
Thank you... for your backup.
好的
Yep.
注意 回见 救护车
See you around, Ratchet.
救护车 到这边来！
Ratchet, come here!
铁堡数据库？
The Iacon database?
它下载到我们的主机上来了！
It's downloading to our mainframe!
哈哈哈！拉斐尔你真是个天才！
Rafael, you are a genius.
哦 相信我
Oh, believe me
声波会破译剩余遗物的坐标的
Soundwave will provide the coordinates to the remaining relics.
是的 拥有他是我们的福气 威震天陛下
Yes, we are fortunate to have him on our side, lord Megatron.
那么你会修复他破损的面甲 不是吗？
And see about repairing his cracked visor, will you?
哼…
Ummm...
隔板回来了 福勒探员
Bulkhead is coming through, Agent Fowler.
我等不及要分享这个消息了！
I can't wait to share the news.
不…！
No!